Total Experience: 12 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computer Science and

Notice Period: 2 Months

Engineering]



Software Development Specialist seeking roles in Software Development, Application Management, Configuration Management, Requirement Gathering, Web Development, Technical Architecture, PHP, MYSQL, JQUERY, JAVASCRIPT, HTML, AGILE, JIRA, Service Delivery



Current Designation: SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

SPECIALIST

Current Company: Integra Micro Software Systems

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Development Specialist, Software Developer, Software Development, Application

Managmenet, Configuration Management, Requirement Gathering, Web Development, Technical Architecture, PHP, MYSQL,

JQUERY, JAVASCRIPT, HTML, AGILE, JIRA, Service Delivery

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

I'm a full stack developer, with more than 12 years of experience in web/application development using several technologies, in multiple domains. I'm actively involve in different phases of Software Development Life-Cycle (SDLC) to deliver a complete solutions for client. I am a public speaker.

Work Experience

Integra Micro Software Systems as SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT SPECIALIST Feb 2016 to Till Date

Deputation at Samsung Research & Development Institute Bangalore, India Feb 2016 to Present (4 years 4 months)

LearningMate Solutions as Module Lead (PHP) - Product Development Dec 2012 to Feb 2016

- Web or Apps Development & Integration Life Cycle
- * Customer Needs Assessment: Requirement Analysis, Optimization & Needed Enhancement
- Risk Management & Quick Resolution of Critical Issues
- * Quick Learner of New Technologies
- Quickly Grasp Concepts & Technical Skills
- * Identify Opportunities for Improvements
- * Confidently & Effectively Under Pressure & Thrives on Challenge
- * Good communicator and good listener
- * Effective Leader: Enlisting Support of all Team Members in Aligning with Project & Organizational Goals.
- Working in Agile Methodology.

Web Development:

LAMP, PHP, MySQL, JQuery, JavaScript, AJAX, OOPs, HTML, CSS, Rest API

Open-source & Framework:

MVC & MVVM, HMVC, Yii, Codeigniter, Laravel, CakePHP

Tools:

SVN, JIRA, GIT, Netbeans, Liquibase, Jenkins

Indus Net Technologies as Sr. Web Developer

Dec 2009 to Dec 2012

Client Communication

Requirement Understanding

Risk Management and Find Solutions - POC Development, if required.

Development

Deployment - Dev, QA and Staging server environment.

Roadmap Achieve & Delivery

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science and Engineering) from West Bengal University of Technology (WBUT) in 2008

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Toastmaster of the Term (Jan-Jun 2020)

Technical and Delivery Performance

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
PHP, SPRING BOOT, REST API			
MICROSERVICES, CODEIGNITER			
Laravel			
MySQL			
Angular, jQuery, JavaScript			
Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3			
MODEL-VIEW-CONTROLLER			
SINGLETON			
git, Jira			
AGILE			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Bengali	Expert			
Hindi	Beginner			

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname = f777e766ef5c171f9a3107d12335ff980e085a59431058450247130d595...

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time